# **Emily Yetsko**

## Front End Developer

emilyyetsko@gmail.com

**\** +1-607-229-5156

in emily-yetsko

eyetsko

emilyyetsko.com

# **B** LANGUAGES

**English** 

••••

Italian

 $\bullet$   $\bullet$   $\bullet$   $\bullet$ 



#### **Web Development**

HTML CSS/SCSS JavaScript Ruby

# Frameworks & Libraries

Rails React Stimulus Bootstrap Node.js

## **Development Tools**

APIs JSON VSCode GitHub

# Design & Collaboration Tools

Figma Airtable SharePoint Microsoft Dynamics Microsoft Suite Asana

#### **Soft Skills**

Project Management Problem Solving Adaptability Teamwork

### **○ PROFILE**

Experienced professional with 8+ years in sales, management, and product development in the fashion industry, making a lateral transition to **front-end development**. Creative problem solver that has worked in startups, and established firms using diverse CRM and PLM tools.

As a recent graduate from **Le Wagon** Web Development Bootcamp I am seeking a front-end development role where learning and growth are supported. I would like to contribute with my years of professional knowledge while I strengthen my coding skills getting exposure on multiple projects, in a collaborative environment.

## PROJECTS

**Safe Travels,** Le Wagon Capstone Project ⊗

- App designed for women to travel safely
- Project Manager 5 person team
- Front-end: HTML, SCSS, JS, API (Rails framework)

Weather App, SheCodes Project ∂

- React based weather app
- Utilized OpenWeatherMap API for real time weather updates
- · React JS, HTML, CSS

### Travel Photography Site *⊘*

- Web design project to showcase my travel photography
- HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Figma

# **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

**Production & Product Development Manager,** *Insider Creations ⊗* Sep 2020 – Dec 2021 New York, US

- Developed/deployed production cycle from initial concept to delivery
- · Coordinated with manufacturing partners in Asia, Europe, and US
- Utilized a CRM to manage proposals, product development, & sales
- Managed 7-person product development and CAD design team

**Account Executive,** International Textile Workshop ∂ Jan 2017 - Sep 2020 | New York, US

- Resolved issues/delays & negotiated payment terms with clients
- Facilitated relationships with factories in Italy, Turkey, and China
- · Worked with VP to develop custom app for fabric sourcing
- Maintained product lifecycle with client and supplier
- Increased sales in my sector by 25%

#### **EDUCATION**

**Le Wagon,** Full-Stack Web Development 2023 | Berlin, DE

**SheCodes,** Front-End Development 2022 | Online

**Fashion Institute of Technology,** BS - Merchandising Management 2013 - 2016 | New York, US

**Polimoda,** International Marketing 2014 - 2015 | Florence, IT